ANDREA WALENS, PhD

CONTACT INFORMATION and rea. walens@gmail.com

Cell: 734-904-2862

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/andreawalens/

Link to CV: https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Vl6ijNqql HNJ-

iXvENepHgHyOSEAOZx/view?usp=sharing

CAREER GOAL

Positively impact the lives of cancer patients by utilizing my expertise in cancer biology, clinical epidemiology, and patient advocacy. With my cross-cutting experience, I aim to facilitate advocacy and policy efforts across disciplines and sectors to address health disparities, treatment outcomes, and overall patient quality of life.

RELEVANT EXPERTISE

- Extensive training and experience in cross-disciplinary research using both mouse and human biological data, patient-level factors, R, and epidemiological methods
- The ability to synthesize a lot of information across disciplines to determine commonalities, next steps, and potential goals
- Strong communication and diplomacy skills, including the ability to raise awareness about an issue or opportunity, and to garner support for a solution by considering others' logistical, intellectual, and cultural needs
- Emotional intelligence born out of empathy and personal experience interacting with cancer patients, survivors, thrivers, and previvors

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Published 3 first-author and 4 co-author articles in peer-reviewed journals and presented at over 20 professional conferences
- Mentored more than 10 high school, undergraduate, and graduate students in both research methods and professional skills
- Successfully lobbied for cancer-related bills that improved patient lives and increased cancer research funding statewide and nationally through ACS CAN
- Lead a small patient support group in the hereditary cancer community for FORCE

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Postdoctoral Fellow, Lineberger Comprehensive Cancer Center, July 2019 – now

Mentorship Course Postdoctoral Teaching Assistant, North Carolina School of Science and

Math, November 2019 – March 2020

Graduate Research Assistant, Duke University, August 2014 – June 2019

EDUCATION

Cancer Control Education Program Postdoctoral Fellowship, Lineberger Comprehensive

Cancer Center, July 2019-June 2021

Overall Project: Immune biomarker development for breast cancer mortality disparities

Ph.D., Molecular Cancer Biology, Duke University, June 2019

Dissertation: The role of the tumor microenvironment in breast cancer dormancy and

recurrence

B.S., Genetics, University of Georgia, May 2014

ADVOCACY WORK

American Cancer Society Cancer Action Network, Legislative Ambassador for NC District 4

American Cancer Society, DetermiNation team member

FORCE, NC Outreach Leader and Peer Navigator

AWARDS AACR Associate Member Award – SABCS

2020

AACR Scholar-In-Training Award

2020 2019

Nominated for Jo Rae Wright Fellowship for Outstanding Women in Science

Ruth Kirschstein Individual National Research Service Award Fellowship 20

2017-2019